Lao Zi once said, “Care about what other people think and you will always be their prisoner.”
老子曾说：“在乎别人怎么想，你就永远是他们的囚徒。”
People-pleasing, or seeking self-worth through others’ approval, is unproductive and an exhausting way to go through life.
讨好他人，也就是通过别人的认可来寻求自我价值，既徒劳无益，又是一种令人疲惫不堪的活法。
Why do we allow what others think of us to have so much power over how we feel about ourselves?
我们为什么要任由别人对我们的看法如此左右我们对自己的感受？
If it’s true that you can’t please all people all of the time, wouldn’t it make sense to stop trying?
如果你确实不可能时时刻刻让所有人都满意，那么不再去尝试难道不是合情合理吗？
Unfortunately, sense often isn’t driving our behavior.
遗憾的是，驱动我们行为的往往并不是理智。
For social beings who desire love and belonging, wanting to be liked and caring about the effect we have on others are healthy and allow us to make connections.
对于渴望爱与归属感的社会性生物而言，想被人喜欢、在乎自己对他人产生的影响，都是健康的，也能让我们与他人建立联系。
However, where we get into trouble is when our self-worth is dependent upon whether we win someone’s approval or not.
然而，一旦我们的自我价值取决于能否赢得某人的认可，我们就会陷入麻烦。
This need to be liked can be traced back to when we were children and were completely dependent on others to take care of us: Small children are not just learning how to walk and communicate; they are also trying to learn how the world works.
这种想被人喜欢的需要，可以追溯到我们还是孩子、完全依赖别人照顾的时候：小孩子不只是在学走路、学与人交流，还在努力弄懂这个世界是如何运转的。
We learn about who we are and what is expected of us based on interactions with others, so, to a four-year-old, if Mommy or Daddy doesn’t like him or her, there is the danger that they will abandon him or her.
我们依据与他人的互动来了解自己是谁、别人对我们有什么期望，所以，在一个四岁的孩子看来，如果妈妈或爸爸不喜欢自己，就有被他们抛弃的危险。
We need to understand that when we desperately want someone to approve of us, it’s being driven by that little-kid part of us that is still terrified of abandonment.
我们需要明白，当我们迫切希望某人认可自己时，驱使这种渴望的是我们内心那个依然极度害怕被抛弃的小孩。
As you become more capable of providing yourself with the approval you seek, your need for external validation will start to vanish, leaving you stronger, more confident, and yes, happier in your life.
随着你越来越能够给予自己所寻求的认可，你对外界肯定的需要就会开始消失，让你变得更坚强、更自信，而且——没错——生活得更快乐。
Imagine how much time we lose each moment we restrain our authentic selves in an effort to be liked.
想象一下，每当我们为了被人喜欢而压抑真实的自我，会失去多少时间。
If we base our worth on the opinions of others, we cheat ourselves of the power to shape our experiences and embrace life not only for others but also for ourselves, because ultimately, there is no difference.
如果我们把自身价值建立在他人的看法上，就等于剥夺了自己塑造自身经历、拥抱生活的能力，而拥抱生活不仅是为了他人，也是为了我们自己，因为归根结底，两者并无区别。
So embrace the cliché and love yourself as it’s highly doubtful that you’ll regret it.
所以，欣然接受这句老话，爱你自己吧，因为你会为此后悔的可能性非常小。